virtualtourist.com 2016-06-16

# privacy statement

The policy below is applicable to all VirtualTourist.com sites and to VirtualTourist.com in general.

Your privacy on the Internet is important to us. We have created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to your privacy. As part of the operations of VirtualTourist.com, we gather certain types of information about VirtualTourist.com users. This VirtualTourist.com Privacy Policy (the "Privacy Policy") explains the types of information we gather, what we do with it and how you may correct or change information that VirtualTourist.com may collect. 

**Information Collected by VirtualTourist.com**  
VirtualTourist.com collects two types of information about users: personal information (such as name and e-mail address) and aggregate information (such as information about how many users log on to our sites on a daily basis). 

**Personal Information**  
Personal information is collected when users voluntarily register for membership services. Personal information includes e-mail addresses, user registration data, passwords, external homepages, gender, birth date, interests, hobbies, travel preferences and any other user data. We may also receive personal usage and demographic information from our third-party partners, and we also collect e-mail addresses from users who send us support mail or request technical or other help. This information enables VirtualTourist.com to improve its sites to make your online visits more productive and enjoyable. 

Our site's registration form requires users to, among other information, give us a valid e-mail address. We use customer e-mail addresses from the registration form to inform you of the status of your Travel Page, new membership benefits and features, to let you know of urgent problems on our site, and to present special members-only opportunities to buy products and services that are appropriate to the interests of our community. 

**Aggregate Information**  
One method of collecting aggregate information about your activities online (such as the pages you access most frequently or the search terms you enter), and information volunteered by you (such as survey or registration information), is by tracking Internet Protocol (IP) addresses. An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you surf the Web. The computers that deliver the Web pages to you automatically identify your computer by its IP address. When you request a page from one of our sites, our servers log your IP address. VirtualTourist.com sites record IP addresses for the purpose of system administration and to provide aggregate data to advertisers about the volume of use on our sites. We also use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our Web site. In addition, your IP address is used to help identify you and to gather broad demographic information. 

**Sharing Data with Third Parties**  
VirtualTourist.com shares aggregate information with third parties for advertising and promotional purposes. VirtualTourist.com may also share personal information with consultants and affiliates for internal business purposes and may divulge personal information if such information is subpoenaed, or if VirtualTourist.com believes that membership has been used to commit unlawful acts, or acts that may endanger the health or safety of another user or of the general public. 

**Use of Cookies**  
VirtualTourist.com sites use 'cookies' to record information. A cookie is a small data file that Web sites store on your hard drive when you visit them. Cookies allow us to measure activity on our sites and to improve your user experience by remembering your passwords and viewing preferences, and allowing you to visit various members-only parts of our sites without re-registering. Cookies allow us to determine which areas and features of our sites are most popular by measuring user activity. This information allows us to make improvements and updates to improve your VirtualTourist.com experience. VirtualTourist.com sites do not use cookies to retrieve any information from your computer. 

Most browsers are set to accept cookies. If you prefer, you may set your browser to refuse cookies or to alert you when cookies are being sent. However, some parts of our sites, such as the members-only areas will not function properly if you choose not to accept cookies. 

**Links to Third Parties**  
This site contains links to sites other than our own. Those sites may not follow the same privacy policies as VirtualTourist.com. Such links may be to advertisers, content providers or partners who may use our logo and/or style as a result of a co-branding or application service provider agreements. These sites may send their own cookies to you, and may collect information and use it in a way inconsistent with VirtualTourist.com's privacy policy. Such sites may contain information that content providers independent of VirtualTourist.com have created, maintained, published, posted or otherwise made available. 

The use of any information or materials that you may access at these external sites is purely voluntary. You should not rely on the contents without independent and thorough review of the accuracy, completeness, effectiveness, timeliness and correct sequencing. These external sites may also refer to specific commercial products, processes, or services by trade name, trademark, service mark, manufacturer or otherwise. Unless VirtualTourist.com has provided explicit authority, such references in no way indicate our endorsement, recommendation or preference. 

VirtualTourist.com also uses a third-party ad company to display ads on our site. These ads may contain cookies. While we use cookies in other parts of our Web site, cookies received with banner ads are collected by our ad company, and we do not have access to this information. 

**Third Party Advertising**

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web site. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements on this site and other sites about goods and services that may be of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please click here http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp 

**Third Party Cookies**  
In the course of serving advertisements to this site, our third-party advertiser may place or recognize a unique "cookie" on your browser. 

**Public Forum**  
Information posted to message boards, chat areas, clubs and home pages is available to the general public and becomes public information. In addition, the site offers to visitors the possibility to provide their own content. PLEASE EXERCISE CAUTION WHEN DECIDING TO DISCLOSE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION. Users under the age of 18 should be particularly careful not to provide any personally identifying information while using chat rooms or message boards. Users of chat areas and message boards must follow acceptable standards of behavior when posting messages online. VirtualTourist.com reserves the right to, but is not obligated to, refuse or delete any content that in our sole discretion is considered inappropriate. 

**Children's Guidelines**  
VirtualTourist.com encourages parents and guardians to spend time with their children online, and to be familiar with the sites their children visit. 

No information is permitted to be either submitted to, or posted on, our sites by users under the age of 13. VirtualTourist.com relies on our users to be truthful in responding to the question of age. VirtualTourist.com will not provide any personally identifying information about users under the age of 13, regardless of its source, to any third party for any purpose whatsoever without first requesting parental permission. 

Our Web site meets the guidelines of TRUSTe's Children's program, since we do not allow children under the age of 13 to become members of our site or publish any personal content or information. 

**Choice to Opt-Out**  
We give users the option to remove their e-mail address from our database at any time and to not receive future communications and to no longer receive the membership benefits of our service. To do so, please send an e-mail to feedback@virtualtourist.com. 

**Correct/Update**  
This site provides users with options for changing and modifying information previously provided.  
You can edit your personal information on your ?Settings? page.   
You can edit the content, provided by you, through ?Edit? links on the corresponding pages or delete the content through ?Delete? links on the corresponding pages. 

**Additional Information**  
No transmission of data over the Internet is guaranteed to be completely secure. It may be possible for third parties not under the control of VirtualTourist.com to intercept or access transmissions or private communications unlawfully. While we strive to protect your personal information, VirtualTourist.com cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us. Any such transmission is done at your own risk. 

Under no circumstances, including but not limited to negligence, shall VirtualTourist.com be liable for any special, incidental or consequential damages that result from the use of the information or materials on VirtualTourist.com sites, even if VirtualTourist.com or an authorized representative of VirtualTourist.com, has been advised of the possibility of such damages. VirtualTourist.com reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time. Any such changes will be posted online. 

USE OF THIS SITE SIGNIFIES YOUR UNDERSTANDING AND AGREEMENT TO COMPLY WITH THE ENTIRE PRIVACY POLICY.

You may also contact us via e-mail and any questions should be directed to feedback@virtualtourist.com.
